# **Stephen Harrold CV**

# **Junior Full Stack Software Developer**

Phone: +353 87 265 5242

Personal Website: https://steharr.github.io/steharr-personal-website/

Email Address: <a href="mailto:steharrold@gmail.com">steharrold@gmail.com</a>

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephen-harrold-338235173/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephen-harrold-338235173/</a>

GitHub: https://github.com/steharr

### **Personal Summary**

I am a highly motivated junior full stack developer currently working for software consultancy firm Version 1. My skills cover the full stack of application development. In my current role I utilize frameworks like Angular for frontend development and Java's Spring for back-end implementation. My expertise is not limited to Java, I have also previously developed full stack applications using the Python Django framework. I have considerable experience working on large scale application development, both on the development side and business side.

#### **Skills**

- Front End: Angular, Typescript, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery
- Back End: Java, Spring Boot, JPA, Hibernate, Python, Flask, Django, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL
- DevOps: Git, Bash, JIRA, Maven, Bamboo, Docker, Weblogic, Heroku, Render
- Other: REST API, Domain Driven Design, NodeJs, Spring MVC, JSP, XML, Intellij, VSCode, Postman, Excel VBA, RPA (UiPath), SAP, CRM (Microsoft Dynamics), MATLAB
- Transferable Skills: Problem Solving, Keen Learner, Project Management, Public Speaking, Leadership, Change Management, Communication, Adaptable

#### **Education**

#### 2021 – 2022: Diploma in Full Stack Software Development, Code Institute (Part Time)

- Learning a variety of font and back-end technologies and using these skills to complete "milestone" projects for assessment with help of industry experienced senior mentor
- Technologies covered: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Git, Python, Flask, Django, MySQL, MongoDB, Heroku

# 2017 – 2018: Masters' Degree in Mechanical and Manufacturing Engineering, Trinity College Dublin, Grade: 72% - Award and Pass

 Completed research dissertation 'Forward Dynamics Modelling of Head Kinematics in Rugby' which involved assessing the accuracy of using crash simulation software MADYMO to detect and prevent concussion in rugby

2013 – 2017: Bachelor's Degree in Mechanical and Manufacturing Engineering, Trinity College Dublin, Grade: 67% - Upper Second Class Honours (2.1)

# **Projects**

#### **Completed Projects:**

#### **Holiday Review Website**

- > Full stack CRUD application created for third "milestone" project for Code Institute course. Received **Merit** grade
- > Technologies used: Python, Flask, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Heroku
- > Github Link: https://github.com/steharr/ms3-holiday-review

#### Escape the Chase

- > Web browser Javascript chasing game with Java Spring back end. Connected to ElephantSQL database for score leaderboards
- > **Technologies used:** Spring MVC, Thymeleaf, Javascript, Spring Data, JPA, PostgreSQL, ElephantSQL, Render
- > Github Link: https://github.com/steharr/chase-game

#### Cat and Mouse JS Game

- > Previous incarnation of 'Escape the chase' game done for course. Front end only.
- > Submitted as second "milestone" project for Code Institute course. Received Merit grade
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS & JavaScript
- > Github Link: <a href="https://github.com/steharr/ms2-cat-and-mouse-game">https://github.com/steharr/ms2-cat-and-mouse-game</a>

# **Work Experience**

#### Jan 2022 – Present: Java Developer, Version 1, Department of Agriculture, Food and the Marine (DAFM)

- Working on 'BISS' (Basic Income Support for Sustainability) application used by Irish farmers nationwide to apply for payments and schemes provided by Irish government.
- Using Java Spring framework for REST API back-end development and Angular framework for the front end
- Collaborating with stakeholders to refine requirements in JIRA
- Developing, testing and maintaining new and existing features in BISS application
- Applying Domain Driven Design (DDD) concepts in the back end to help create robust and agile infrastructure
- Maintaining builds and releases into Development, Testing and UAT environments using **Bamboo**.

# April 2021 - Jan 2022: Order Management Key User, Infineon Technologies

- Product owner for global RPA (Robotic Process Automation) shipping bot which automated ~10,000 weekly supply chain shipments in SAP ERP system
- Determined requirements for multiple change requests in collaboration with business and development team
- Conducted user acceptance testing for changes and debugged issues
- Also worked as VBA Developer automating various manual tasks incl. report generation, database maintenance & email sending.

# April 2019 – April 2021: Transition Coordinator, Infineon Technologies

- Coordinated set up of SAP order management team to support employees in six offices across Europe
- Primary change agent for European region collaborating with employees of all six offices; promoting progress, communicating updates and addressing feedback
- Worked on standardizing processes, contributed to RPA automation projects & developed VBA macros to automate spreadsheet workflows

#### **Hobbies and Interests**

#### Sport

- Soccer player Regularly participate in 5 a side matches with friends. I've previously managed and played for social 11 a side team while in university.
- Former rugby player Represented my province (Leinster) at youth level. Won Leinster Schools Senior Cup in 2012 with my school team.

#### Art

• I enjoy painting and drawing in my spare time. I also enjoy going to museums and attending drawing classes. During my time in university, I worked for commission on various painting projects for friends and family.

References available upon request